Guide to the Edna St. Vincent Millay Papers, 1892-1988
Archives and Special Collections Library, Vassar College Libraries
Edna St. Vincent Millay Papers
1892-1988
Millay, Edna St. Vincent, 1892-1950
7 cubic feet (29 boxes)
Archives and Special Collections Library, Vassar College Libraries
Examinations, student papers, accounts, programs, publications, and photographs from her years at Vassar College, circa 1913-1917; manuscripts of two poems; and forty-five letters to Elizabeth Hazelton Haight, Vassar President Henry Noble MacCracken, Walter Adolphe Roberts, Charlotte Babcock Sills, and others. Also includes letters of husband Eugen Boissevain, Mrs. A.W. Parsons (Millay's "Auntie Kem) and others. The remainder of the collection consists of published works by Millay or material about her life and career, such as her involvement in the Sacco-Vanzetti murder trial, and includes photographs, articles, clippings, reviews, programs.
Biographical Note
Edna St. Vincent Millay was born February 22, 1892, in Rockland, ME. Her mother, Cora Lounella Buzzelle Millay, raised "Vincent" -- as she was known to family and close friends--and her younger sisters, Norma (b. 1893) and Kathleen (b. 1896), primarily on her own after a divorce from Millay's father, Henry Tolman Millay, in 1900. Millay's literary career began in 1906 when her poem, "Forest Trees," was accepted and published in St. Nicholas magazine. Millay became a regular contributor to St. Nicholas until she turned 18 and could no longer submit her works. In 1912, "Renascence" was accepted for publication in a poetry anthology, The Lyric Year. Millay was encouraged to continue her formal education and she entered Vassar College in September, 1913 at age twenty-one following a semester of preparatory study at Columbia University's Barnard College.
During her Vassar years, Millay wrote and appeared in several plays for Vassar College productions. She also wrote music and lyrics for Vassar events including "The Patient Periodical," that won the Class Song Contest in 1916, and the Class of 1917 Baccalaureate Hymn. Millay had little tolerance for the rules and regulations imposed on students at Vassar in those days. She was banned from participating in Commencement exercises because she had been caught staying out of town overnight, but a protest effort by friends--both student and faculty--managed to persuade the administration to permit her to attend the ceremonies. It was a disheartening end to a difficult four years, but Millay was pleased with her accomplishment of graduating from Vassar. Millay's first book of poetry, Renascence and Other Poems, was published by Mitchell Kennerley in December 1917. After finishing at Vassar, Millay moved to Greenwich Village and pursued writing and acting with the Provincetown Players, including performances of some of her own works. During this time, Millay also published a series of short stories in Ainslee's magazine under the pseudonym "Nancy Boyd" to supply income.
In 1923 Millay won the Pulitzer Prize for Poetry for her "Ballad of the Harpweaver." That same year she married Eugen Jan Boissevain (1880-1949) who encouraged and supported Millay's creative and literary pursuits. Millay and Boissevain bought Steepletop, a farm near Austerlitz, NY, in 1925 and lived there for the remainder of their lives. Millay was an immensely popular poet selling over three quarters of a million copies of her books during her lifetime. Through the 1920s and 1930s she gave numerous public readings of her poetry, both in live appearances and radio broadcasts, which afforded her public recognition and critical acknowledgment. Millay involved herself in social and political issues throughout her career: feminism, the injustice of the Sacco and Vanzetti affair, and the issues of World War II all received the attention of her pen. In addition to her works of short lyric and sonnet poetry, Millay wrote several plays including The King's Henchman, one of the most recognized American operatic works of this century. Millay died of heart failure on 19 October 1950, at her home in Austerlitz, NY.
Scope and Content Note
The Millay Collection at the Vassar College Libraries Department of Special Collections is an artificial collection assembled from Vassar College administrative files, professor and instructor records, donations from friends and fellow Class of 1917 alumnae, and donations from admirers and associates of Millay. The researcher should be aware that there are no personal papers of Millay and few manuscript materials from Millay.
The strength of the Millay Collection is in documenting the time Millay spent at Vassar College, 1913-1917, and her activities during that period. Vassar College administrative files, official correspondence, academic records, student activities' materials, and professor records constitute the formal documentation for the Collection. These records are enhanced by papers from Professor Elizabeth Hazelton Haight. Elizabeth Hazelton Haight, professor of Latin and the Classics at Vassar from 1909-1942, first met Millay during the summer of 1913. She tutored Millay in Latin in preparation for the Vassar College entrance examinations, and the two remained close both personally as friends and formally as professor and student. Professor Haight's materials include research she compiled for two articles she wrote about Millay, "Vincent at Vassar" and "Vincent at Steepletop." Documentation of the relationship between Millay and Vassar is supplemented by materials donated by friends and classmates, most notably Charlotte Babcock Sills who was one of Millay's roommates and close friends at Vassar. The Collection also contains a number of photographs of Vassar College Productions of Millay's works and performances by Millay while at Vassar.
Millay's literary works are represented by letters and manuscript items from Mitchell Kennerley, Millay's first publisher (Renascence and Other Poems), and Walter Adolphe Roberts, editor of Ainslee's magazine. In addition, several radio broadcast scripts and letters from the files of Margaret Cuthbert document Millay's poetry readings and public response.
Papers from Margaret Cuthbert and Alice Blinn contain information about Millay's career and personal affairs. It is not clear how or when these two women met Millay and Eugen Boissevain, but correspondence with "Aunt Edna" and "Uncle Ugin" spans a twenty-six year period, from 1924 to 1950. Margaret Cuthbert was on staff at NBC Radio, New York during the period when Millay did several broadcasts with NBC. Alice Blinn was an editor at Ladies' Home Journal, and involved Ladies' Home Journal in a project to renovate the kitchen at Steepletop for an article published in 1947. Records from this venture, includes photographs of the project and are in the Collection. Millay's childhood and early life is also documented in photographs and letters containing reminiscences from Millay's "Auntie Kem," Clementine Parsons, to Margaret Cuthbert and Alice Blinn, and Elizabeth Hazelton Haight.
Contents note: "Clippings" files contain items cut from all types of sources-- newspapers, journals, magazines, newsletters, etc. All sorts of items are clipped including articles, announcements of readings, publication ads, articles about family members and friends, publication reviews, announcements of honorary degrees, announcements of stage productions, film negotiations, obituaries, literary awards and affairs, drawings, etc. Some files also contain full issues of magazines with articles about Millay. A large cache of published material was transferred from the Archive's Alumnae Collection in 2005. The bulk of that material is now included in the "Contributions to Periodicals" section of Series IV, but there were also additions to the clippings in Series VII, and the "Musical Adaptations" section of Series VIII.
Access
This collection is open for research according to the regulations of the Vassar College Archives and Special Collections Library without any additional restrictions.
Related Materials
Anne Gardner Edna St. Vincent Millay Collection
John S. Van E. Kohn Edna St. Vincent Millay Collection
For additional photos of Millay, see:
VC Photo Files - V.C. Students. Dramatics
Student Materials, photo album no. 300
Subject Headings
Names:
Boissevain, Eugen, -1949; Dillon, George, 1906-1968; Haight, Elizabeth Hazelton, 1872-1964; MacCracken, H. N. (Henry Noble), 1880-1970; Parsons, A.W., Mrs.; Roberts, Walter Adolphe, 1886-1962; Sills, Charlotte Babcock
Organizations:
Vassar College--Students; Vassar College--Alumni and alumnae
Subjects:
American literature--Women authors; Poets, American--20th century; Sacco-Vanzetti Trial, Dedham, Mass., 1921; Women poets--United States
Document Types:
Clippings (information artifacts); Correspondence; Photographs; Poems; Realia; Scrapbooks; Sheet music
VCL Categories:
Literature and Writing; Vassar College
Encoding Information
Encoded by Elizabeth Clarke, April 2007. Last updated by Emma Gronbeck, September 2024.
Acquisition Information
A combination of transfers from various Vassar offices, gifts of private donors, and purchases.
Additions made November 2003 (M2003-010) May 2005 (M2005-011); April 2006 (M2006-005, M2006-006 as well as materials moved from Vassar Alumnae Collection); May 2009 (M2009-010); March 2012 (M2012-002); June 2014 (M2014-010); October 2021 (M2021-016); January 2024 (M2024-001); and September 2024 (M2024-014).
Series List
- Series I. CORRESPONDENCE, 1917-1965; (Boxes 1-4)
- Series II. MILLAY AND VASSAR COLLEGE, 1912-1965; (Boxes 4-7)
- Series III. MANUSCRIPTS, circa 1913-1940; (Boxes 8 and 13)
- Series IV. WORKS BY MILLAY, 1906-1956; (Boxes 9-10, 25, 26, and 28)
- Series V. BIBLIOGRAPHICAL MATERIAL, 1928-1986; (Boxes 10 and 13)
- Series VI. LITERARY REVIEWS AND CRITICISM, 1918-1969; (Boxes 10-11, 28)
- Series VII. BIOGRAPHICAL AND COMMEMORATIVE MATERIAL, circa 1892-[1992]; (Boxes 11-12, 21, 26, 28)
- Series VIII. PRODUCTIONS OF WORKS BY AND ABOUT MILLAY, 1923-1981; (Boxes 12-13, 27)
- Series IX. PHOTOGRAPHS, circa 1892-1958; (Boxes 14-21)
- Series X. SCRAPBOOKS, undated; (Boxes 22-23)
- Series XI. REALIA, 1955-1957; (Boxes 21, 24, 29)
Container List
- SERIES I: CORRESPONDENCE
  - Millay Letters to Others
    - Millay to Elizabeth Hazelton Haight, 1917-1938, undated; (10 letters) (Folder 1.1)
    - Millay to Burges Johnson, [1918]; (1 letter) (Folder 1.2)
    - Millay to Mitchell Kennerley, 1928, undated; (4 letters, 1 clipping, 2p., 1 note) (Folder 1.3)
    - Millay to Amy L. Reed, [1946], undated; (1 letter, 1 note) (Folder 1.4)
    - Millay to Walter Adolphe Roberts, 1918-1920, undated; (14 letters) (Folder 1.5)
    - Millay to Charlotte Babcock Sills, 1917-1941; (8 letters) (Folder 1.6)
    - Millay to Charlotte Babcock Sills. Transcriptions of letters, inscriptions, 1917-1940; (3 p.) (Folder 1.7)
    - Millay to Charlotte Babcock Sills, [1917]; (1 letter) (Folder 1.8)
    - Millay correspondence with Margaret Cuthbert and Alice Blinn (letters, cables, carbons, notes), 1927-1938; (14 items) (Folder 1.9)
    - Millay correspondence with Margaret Cuthbert and Alice Blinn, 1941-1949; (9 items) (Folder 1.10)
    - Millay correspondence with Margaret Cuthbert and Alice Blinn, 1950, undated; (13 items) (Folder 1.11)
    - Millay to Margaret Cuthbert and Alice Blinn, 1930; (2 Christmas cards) (Folder 1.12)
    - Millay to Walter L. Fleisher, 14 Feb 1921; (1 letter) (Folder 1.14)
    - Millay to Eugene F. Saxton, 1932, 1934; (3 letters) (Folder 1.15)
    - Millay to Margaret L. Burns, 1924; (2 letters) (Folder 1.17)
    - Millay to Mary Kennedy, 1938; (1 letter) (Folder 1.18)
    - Millay to G.D. Bergonzi, 1944; (1 letter) (Folder 1.19)
      (Written on reverse of page two of letter from Eugene Boissevain to Bergonzi)
    - Millay to George Dillon, 1928 Dec - 1929 Oct; (4 letters) (Folder 1.20)
  - Correspondence about Millay
    - Boissevain, Eugen correspondence with Margaret Cuthbert and Alice Blinn (NOTE: Some items annotated by Millay, many undated), 1924-1927; (10 items) (Folder 1.13)
    - Boissevain, Eugen correspondence with Margaret Cuthbert and Alice Blinn, 1928-1930; (8 items) (Folder 2.1)
    - Boissevain, Eugen correspondence with Margaret Cuthbert and Alice Blinn, 1931-1936; (8 items) (Folder 2.2)
    - Boissevain, Eugen correspondence with Margaret Cuthbert and Alice Blinn, 1937-1940; (8 items) (Folder 2.3)
    - Boissevain, Eugen correspondence with Margaret Cuthbert and Alice Blinn, 1941-1949; (10 items) (Folder 2.4)
    - Boissevain, Eugen correspondence with Margaret Cuthbert and Alice Blinn, undated; (14 items) (Folder 2.5)
    - Boissevain, Eugen correspondence with Margaret Cuthbert and Alice Blinn, undated; (12 items) (Folder 2.6)
    - Boissevain, Eugen correspondence with Margaret Cuthbert and Alice Blinn, undated; (10 items) (Folder 2.7)
    - Cuthbert, Margaret, correspondence about Millay, 1929-1950; (23 items) (Folder 2.8)
    - Cuthbert, Margaret, correspondence about Millay, 1951-1965; (8 items) (Folder 2.9)
    - Boissevain, Eugen correspondence with Alice Blinn about Kitchen at Steepletop, [1947]; (notes, 3 p., 1 telegram, 11 letters) (Folder 2.10)
    - Boissevain, Eugen correspondence with Alice Blinn about Kitchen at Steepletop, 1948-1949; (19 letters) (Folder 2.11)
    - Boissevain, Eugen to Lenore F. Jacobson, 28 Nov 1949; (1 letter) (Folder 2.12)
    - Boissevain, Eugen to Mr. and Mrs. Harry Kaufman, 1936; (2 letters) (Folder 3.13)
    - Kennerley, Mitchell to R. J. [Roy] Cook, 10 Aug 1923; (1 letter) (Folder 2.13)
    - Monroe, Harriet to "Dr. Laing,", 6 Apr 1936; (1 letter) (Folder 2.14)
    - Parsons, Clementine to Margaret Cuthbert and Alice Blinn, 1951-1953; (6 letters) (Folder 3.1)
    - Parsons, Clementine to Margaret Cuthbert and Alice Blinn, 1954; (5 letters) (Folder 3.2)
    - Parsons, Clementine to Elizabeth Hazelton Haight, 1953-1956; (7 letters) (Folder 3.3)
    - Parsons, Clementine to Elizabeth Hazelton Haight, 1957; (16 letters) (Folder 3.4)
    - Parsons, Clementine to Elizabeth Hazelton Haight, 1958-1959; (14 letters, 2 post cards) (Folder 3.5)
    - Letters to Elizabeth Hazelton Haight, 1951-1958; (11 letters) (Folder 3.6)
    - Boissevain, Eugen to Walter Adolphe Roberts, 1926; (1 letter) (Folder 3.7)
    - Roberts, Walter Adolphe correspondence with Cora Millay, 1929; (2 letters) (Folder 3.8)
    - Roberts, Walter Adolphe correspondence regarding Allan Ross MacDougall's Letters (with Allan Ross MacDougall), 1951-1952; (7 letters) (Folder 3.9)
    - Roberts, Walter Adolphe correspondence regarding Allan Ross MacDougall's Letters (with Solita Solano), 1951-1952; (5 letters) (Folder 3.10)
    - Letters to NBC Radio and Miss Millay, 1932-1933; (42 items) (Folder 3.11)
    - Letters to NBC Radio and Miss Millay, 1932-1933; (44 items) (Folder 3.12)
    - Two letters to J. Paget-Fredericks, one from A. W. Rushmore and the other from Virginia Kirkus, along with 3 unassociated envelopes from Steepletop, 1932, 1938; (5 items) (Folder 3.12)
    - Photostats of cable and letters, Millay to FDR, 1940; (3 items) (Folder 4.1)
    - Photoprint images of letters, Millay to Miss Brigham, 1949; (2 letters) (Folder 4.2)
    - Millay to Secretary, NYU (typed transcription), 22 May 1937; (3 p.) (Folder 4.3)
    - Millay to Cass Canfield (typed carbon copy), 8 Jan 1946; (5 p.) (Folder 4.4)
    - Christmas Cards from Millay, 1949, undated; (2 items) (Folder 4.5)
- SERIES II: MILLAY AND VASSAR COLLEGE
  - Administrative and Academic Affairs
    - Correspondence with Henry Noble MacCracken, 1915-1921; (2 ALS, 1 TLS, 4 cc to Millay) (Folder 4.6)
    - Correspondence with Ella McCaleb, Dean, 1915; (1 ALS, 1 cc) (Folder 4.7)
    - Bill in files of President's Office, undated; (1 note) (Folder 4.8)
    - Information from Barnard College and Correspondence, 1912-1913, 1951; (17 items) (Folder 4.9)
    - Millay's Vassar College Admission Folder, 1913-1914; (11 items) (Folder 4.10)
    - Courses at Vassar, 1913-1917; (2 p.) (Folder 4.11)
    - History Entrance Exam and note, 1913, 1951; (7 p.) (Folder 4.12)
    - German A Examination [short course] and memoir of Professor Jenney, [1914?], 1951; (2 items) (Folder 4.13)
    - History D Examination, Feb 1916; (2 parts) (Folder 4.14)
    - Topic prepared for English L [Shakespeare Course], 1916; (40 note cards) (Folder 4.15)
    - Signature on Library book card, undated; (2 items) (Folder 4.16)
  - Student Affairs
    - Undergraduate Publications — lists, notes, article: "Some Undergraduate Printings of Edna St. Vincent Millay,", undated; (7 items) (Folder 4.17)
    - Class Songs — "Song of the Nations", "Fall in Line," and correspondence, [1915-1917], 1964; (10 p.) (Folder 4.18)
    - Class Songs — "Patient Periodical,", [1916]; (2 items) (Folder 4.19)
    - Class Songs — Baccalaureate Hymn — "St. Vincent" and Correspondence, 1917, 1935, 1958; (7 items) (Folder 5.1)
    - Commencement, 1917; (6 items) (Folder 5.2)
    - Correspondence from Dean's Office regarding Millay's graduation, undated; (3 letters) (Folder 5.3)
    - Letter to editor regarding "night out,", 1960; (2 items) (Folder 5.4)
    - Millay's extracurricular activities, undated; (2 items) (Folder 5.5)
  - Dramatic Productions
    - Dramatic Productions at Vassar, 1915-1917; (3 items) (Folder 5.6)
    - "Princess of Pretencia," 1917 Sophomore Party, [24 Oct 1914]; (2 programs) (Folder 5.7)
    - "Les Romantiques,", [27 Feb 1915]; (2 items) (Folder 5.8)
    - "Candida,", [6 Mar 1915]; (5 items) (Folder 5.9)
    - "Sophomore Tree Ceremonies,", [May 1915]; (4 items) (Folder 5.10)
    - "Pageant of Athena,", [Oct 1915]; (3 items) (Folder 5.11)
    - "First Hall Play,", [Dec 1916]; (7 items) (Folder 5.12)
    - Second Hall Play — "Deidre of the Sorrows,", [March 1916]; (5 items) (Folder 5.13)
    - "The Princess Marries the Page,", May 1917; (5 items) (Folder 5.14)
  - "Vincent at Vassar"
    - Elizabeth Hazelton Haight's notes – miscellaneous, undated; (35 p.) (Folder 6.1)
    - Elizabeth Hazelton Haight's notes – miscellaneous, undated; (10 items) (Folder 6.2)
    - Elizabeth Hazelton Haight's notes - education, classical influence, undated; (46 items) (Folder 6.3)
    - "Vincent at Vassar" business correspondence, 1951; (24 items) (Folder 6.4)
    - "Vincent at Vassar" author's proof copy; envelope, undated; (2 items) (Folder 6.5)
    - "Vincent at Vassar" reprint and correspondence, 1953-1960; (14 items) (Folder 6.6)
    - Haight, Elizabeth Hazelton, notes - "Theme and Variation" by Millay and correspondence, 1953; (43 p.) (Folder 6.7)
    - Transcription — "Theme and Variation,", undated; (28 p.) (Folder 6.8)
  - Vassar College and Millay after Graduating
    - Class of 1917 Bulletin — "First Reunion Bulletin:, undated; (1 item) (Folder 7.1)
    - Class of 1917 Second Bulletin: "Gossip from the Front,", undated; (1 item) (Folder 7.2)
    - Class of 1917 Third Bulletin: "The Patient Periodica-al,", Sep 1919; (1 item) (Folder 7.3)
    - Class of 1917 Fourth Bulletin: "The Patient Periodical,", Apr 1921; (1 item) (Folder 7.4)
    - Millay's Return visits to Vassar, 1920-1924; (5 items) (Folder 7.5)
    - "The Lamp and the Bell" — program, 18 Jun 1921; (2 items) (Folder 7.6)
    - "The Lamp and the Bell" — correspondence regarding the score, 1931; (2 items) (Folder 7.7)
    - Third Hall Play — "The King's Henchman", program, 1929; (3 items) (Folder 7.8)
    - Vassar College Players — "Aria da Capo", "Two Slatterns and a King,", 1921; (14 items) (Folder 7.9)
    - Vassar College Poetry Broadcast, 1933; (1 item) (Folder 7.10)
    - Correspondence regarding songs by Millay for Class of 1917 Reunion, 1954; (5 items) (Folder 7.11)
    - Vassar College Music Recital, includes "The Snare" by Millay, 6 May 1954; (2 items) (Folder 7.12)
    - Vassar Millay Society, 1965; (3 items) (Folder 7.13)
- SERIES III: MANUSCRIPTS
  - Literary Works
    - "Daphne" [first published in Ainslee's, Nov 1918], undated; (TS, 1p.) (Folder 8.1)
    - "Departure" [first published in Ainslee's, Aug 1919], undated; (MS, 2 p.) (Folder 8.2)
    - "Alms" [first published in Ainslee's, Jun 1919], undated; (MS, 2 p.) (Folder 8.3)
    - "Bereavement,", undated; (TS, 1 p.; excerpt, 1 p.) (Folder 8.4)
    - "Roosevelt's Promises Buried,", undated; (TS, 1 p.) (Folder 13.1)
    - "Ancient Jar,", undated; (TA, 1 p.; letter, 1 p.) (Folder 8.5)
    - Millay to Ella McCaleb, undated; (ANS, 2p.; MS, 1 p.) (Folder 8.6)
    - "Two Slatterns and a King,", undated; (TS, 11 p.; N, 1 p.) (Folder 8.7)
    - "Aria da Capo,", undated; (TS, 21 p.) (Folder 8.8)
    - Unpublished sonnet, "Little friend, come back...,", circa 1913-1917; (MS, 2 p) (Folder 8.18)
    - The Princess Marries the Page — draft of the preface, 1932; (MSs, 3 p) (Folder 1.16)
  - Proofs, annotated
    - "Aria da Capo" [galley proof, MS suggestions], [1921]; (9 p.) (Folder 13.2)
    - "Aria da Capo" — suggestions for production, letter, undated; (TS, 12 p. and ALS, 1 p.) (Folder 8.9)
    - Second April — Author's corrected proofs, [1921]; (1 item) (Folder 13.8)
  - Inscriptions/Autographs
    - Millay inscriptions to Charlotte Sills, Dec 1940 (Folder 8.10)
    - Millay Christmas Card, 1930, (1 item) (Folder 8.11)
    - Millay Christmas Card, 1930, (2 items) (Folder 8.12)
  - Typed Manuscripts of Radio Scripts
    - "Lines Written in Passion and in Deep Concern for England, France, and my Own Country" [from Margaret Cuthbert's files], undated; (TS, 5 p.) (Folder 8.13)
    - "The Christ Child's Miracle" [from Margaret Cuthbert's files], [1942?]; (TS, 17 p.; N, 1 p.) (Folder 8.14)
    - Poems, commentary [by Millay?] [from Margaret Cuthbert's files], undated; (4 items) (Folder 8.15)
    - "Statement by Miss Millay" [from Margaret Cuthbert's files], undated; (3 p.) (Folder 8.16)
    - "Rolls and Salt (A Distressing Dialogue)" [radio broadcast script (?), from Margaret Cuthbert's files], 3 Feb 1937; (9 p.) (Folder 8.17)
    - "For Winter, For Summer (A Distressing Dialogue)" [radio broadcast scripts (?), from Margaret Cuthbert's files], undated; (7 p.) (Folder 13.3)
- SERIES IV: WORKS BY MILLAY
  - Contributions to Periodicals, etc.
    - "Forest Trees," St. Nicholas, 1906; (1 item) (Folder 9.1)
    - "The Land of Romance," St. Nicholas, 1907; (2 items) (Folder 9.2)
    - "After the Celebration," St. Nicholas, 1907; (1 item) (Folder 9.3)
    - "Vacation Song," St. Nicholas, 1907; (1 item) (Folder 9.4)
    - "Life," St. Nicholas, 1908; (1 item) (Folder 9.5)
    - "Day's Rest Time," St. Nicholas, 1908; (1 item) (Folder 9.6)
    - "Young Mother Hubbard," St. Nicholas, 1909; (2 items) (Folder 9.7)
    - "Friends," St. Nicholas, 1910; (2 items) (Folder 9.8)
    - "Interim," Vassar Miscellany, 1914; (1 item) (Folder 9.9)
    - "Barbara on the Beach," Smart Set, 1914; (1 item) (Folder 9.10)
    - "Bluebeard," The Forum, 1916; (1 item) (Folder 9.11)
    - "The Patient Periodical," Vassar Miscellany, 1916; (1 item (clipping)) (Folder 9.12)
    - "The Patient Periodical," Vassar Miscellany, 1916; (1 journal) (Folder 26.5 (Oversize))
    - "The Suicide," Vassar Miscellany, 1916; (1 item) (Folder 9.13)
    - "The Suicide," Vassar Quarterly, 1916; (1 item) (Folder 9.14)
    - "Why Did I Ever Come to this Place," Vassar Miscellany, 1916; (1 item) (Folder 9.15)
    - "Why Did I Ever Come to this Place," Vassar Miscellany, 1916; (1 item) (Folder 28.3 (Oversize))
    - "The Wall of Dominoes," Vassar Miscellany, 1917; (2 items) (Folder 9.16)
    - Baccalaureate Hymn, Vassar Baccalaureate, 1917; (2 items) (Folder 9.17)
    - "Kin to Sorrow" and 2 others, Poetry, 1917; (1 item) (Folder 9.18)
    - "Not in this Chamber..." Pan American Magazine, 1918; (1 item) (Folder 9.19)
    - "Figs from Thistles, Poetry, 1918; (1 item) (Folder 9.20)
    - "Ashes of Life" and "The Shroud," Pan American Magazine, 1918; (1 item) (Folder 9.21)
    - "Possession," The Sonnet, 1918; (1 item) (Folder 9.22)